Finding Aid for Letters, Documents, & Other Manuscripts, Duane Norman Diedrich Collection, 1595-2007
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
Letters, Documents, & Other Manuscripts, Duane Norman Diedrich collection 1595-20071719-1945
Diedrich, Duane Norman, Letters, Documents, & Other Manuscripts
Diedrich, D. N. (Duane Norman), 1935-2018
3.5 linear feet
wclmss002497
The Letters, Documents, and Other Manuscripts of the Duane Norman Diedrich Collection is a selection of individual items compiled by manuscript collector Duane Norman Diedrich (1935-2018) and the William L. Clements Library. The content of these materials reflect the life and interests of D. N. Diedrich, most prominently subjects pertinent to intellectual, artistic, and social history, education, speech and elocution, the securing of speakers for events, advice from elders to younger persons, and many others.
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
1970-2017. M-1523, M-1727, M-1812, M-1829, M-1858, M-1864, M-1884, M-1893, M-1898, M-1900, -1902, M-1907, M-1923, M-1924, M-1949, M-1950, M-1957, M-1958, M-1968, M-1990, M-2013, M-2014, M-2015, M-2017, M-2019, M-2026, M-2034, M-2055, M-2057, M-2060, M-2074, M-2078, M-2111, M-2118, M-2122, M-2125, M-2144, M-2161, M-2171, M-2175, M-2209, M-2215, M-2226, M-2240, M-2257, M-2258, M-2259, M-2291, M-2308, M-2311, M-2321, M-2371, M-2373, M-2384, M-2389, M-2396, M-2400, M-2443, M-2443a, M-2443b, M-2443l, M-2443m, M-2443o, M-2489, M-2490.3, M-2491, M-2503, M-2508, M-2514, M-2520e, M-2520h, M-2538, M-2637, M-2662, M-2662a28, M-2673, M-2682, M-2688, M-2710, M-2710c, M-2710d, M-2710e, M-2710h, M-2710i, M-2710k, M-2710l, M-2712.1, M-2714.3, M-2714.12, M-2714.13, M-2714.20, M-2715.1, M-2724.3, M-2725.1, M-2725.2, M-2725.3, M-2725.4, M-2729.1, M-2731.3, M-2737.5, M-2787.3, M-2793, M-2797, M-2807.1, M-2812, M-2812.1, M-2812.3, M-2839, M-2843.2, M-2859, M-2862, M-2862.1, M-2876.1, M-2876.2, M-2880, M-2891.17, M-2892.3, M-2898, M-2898.2, M-2898.3, M-2907, M-2939.4, M-2947.38, M-2975.13, M-2975.6, M-2980.2, M-2980.4, M-2984.6, M-2995.1, M-2999.4, M-3001.5, M-3001.6, M-3006.3, M-3006.4, M-3006.6, M-3006.13, M-3006.18, M-3006.28, M-3011.1, -3011.3, M-3013.4, M-3016.3, M-3017.1, M-3030.3, M-3046.1, M-3046.2, M-3082.3, M-3093, M-3119.1, M-3120.3, M-3120.7, M-3125, M-3132.2, M-3145.3, M-3159.4, M-3160.2, M-3163, M-3176.3, M-3193.1, M-3193.2, M-3198.6, M-3208.7, M-3219.2, M-3223.6, M-3227.2, M-3228.5, M-3240, M-3279, M-3287, M-3290, M-3298.2, M-3299.1, M-3299.2, M-3299.3, M-3301.3, M-3301.7, M-3312.2, M-3312.3, M-3322.1, M-3327.2, M-3334, M-3342, M-3360, M-3377.1, M-3377.3, M-3377.4, M-3404, M-3443.1, M-3445.3, M-3449.5, M-3449.6, M-3458.5, M-3458.6, M-3460, M-3460.7, M-3476.2, M-3476.4, M-3490, M-3495, M-4009.16, M-4009.2, M-4028, M-4032.1, M-4032.4, M-4052, M-4069, M-4078, M-4106.7, M-4115.2, M-4116.21, M-4121, M-4167, M-4170.1, M-4171.7, M-4173.1, M-4173.3, M-4173.4, M-4173.5, M-4179.2, M-4179.3, M-4191.1, M-4191.3, M-4191.6, M-4263, M-4272.5, M-4293.2, M-4304.5, M-4306.2, M-4306.6, M-4318.2, M-4334, M-4335.1, M-4335.2, M-4336.3, M-4337.2, M-4338.12, M-4338.14, M-4338.16, M-4338.17, M-4338.18, M-4338.19, M-4338.20, M-4338.21, M-4338.24, M-4338.25, M-4338.26, M-4338.27, M-4338.28, M-4338.29, M-4338.3, M-4338.6, M-4341.1, M-4345.1, M-4348.4, M-4348.7, M-4349.1, M-4356.10, M-4356.11, M-4356.13, M-4356.2, M-4356.4, M-4356.5, M-4356.6, M-4356.7, M-4358.3, M-4370, M-4389, M-4397.1, M-4399.3, M-4400.1, M-4400.9, M-4408.5, M-4409.16, M-4439.10, M-4454.1, M-4454.2, M-4454.3, M-4454.4, M-4454.6, M-4454.7, M-4454.8, M-4456, M-4458.1, M-4507.37, M-4507.39, M-4531.1, M-4531.15, M-4531.2, M-4531.3, M-4531.4, M-4531.5, M-4531.8, M-4547.12, M-4547.13, M-4547.15, M-4547.16, M-4547.18, M-4547.2, M-4547.24, M-4547.25, M-4547.4, M-4547.7, M-4547.8, M-4547.9, M-4559.2, M-4566.1, M-4566.2, M-4566.3, M-4566.4, M-4566.5, M-4566.6, M-4566.7, M-4566.9, M-4583.2, M-4600.1, M-4600.10, M-4600.11, M-4600.22, M-4600.23, M-4600.24, M-4600.25, M-4600.26, M-4600.27, M-4600.28, M-4600.31, M-4600.32, M-4600.35, M-4600.4, M-4600.42, M-4600.43, M-4600.44, M-4600.45, M-4600.46, M-4600.47, M-4600.48, M-4600.49, M-4600.50, M-4600.51, M-4600.7, M-4600.8, M-4622.1, M-4622.100, M-4622.101, M-4622.12, M-4622.13, M-4622.14, M-4622.15, M-4622.16, M-4622.17, M-4622.18, M-4622.19, M-4622.2, M-4622.20, M-4622.23, M-4622.25, M-4622.26, M-4622.27, M-4622.28, M-4622.34, M-4622.36, M-4622.37, M-4622.38, M-4622.39, M-4622.40, M-4622.41, M-4622.42, M-4622.44, M-4622.46, M-4622.47, M-4622.48, M-4622.5, M-4622.50, M-4622.51, M-4622.52, M-4622.54, M-4622.55, M-4622.57, M-4622.58, M-4622.59, M-4622.62, M-4622.63, M-4622.65, M-4622.66, M-4622.70, M-4622.73, M-4622.76, M-4622.78, M-4622.79, M-4622.8, M-4622.85, M-4622.85, M-4622.86, M-4622.87, M-4622.88, M-4622.89, M-4622.9, M-4622.90, M-4622.91, M-4622.92, M-4622.94, M-4622.96, M-4622.96, M-4622.97, M-4622.98, M-4622.99, M-4623.2, M-4623.3, M-4630, M-4632.1, M-4632.10, M-4632.12, M-4632.2, M-4632.3, M-4632.5, M-4632.6, M-4632.7, M-4632.9, M-4633, M-4634.2, M-4634.3, M-4635.1, M-4635.10, M-4635.11, M-4635.4, M-4635.5, M-4635.6, M-4636.1, M-4636.2, M-4636.4, M-4636.6, M-4636.7, M-4636.8, M-4639.2, M-4639.3, M-4639.4, M-4642.2, M-4642.6, M-4642.7, M-4643.6, M-4652.4, M-4654.2, M-4657, M-4658.2, M-4658.3, M-4663, M-4668.1, M-4671.1, M-4672.1, M-4676.1, M-4676.4, M-4678.2, M-4678.4, M-4681.3, M-4685.3, M-4698.2, M-4698.3, M-4741, M-4751.1, M-4751.2, M-4751.3, M-4751.4, M-4752.3, M-4752.5, M-4765.1, M-4767.1, M-4767.2, M-4767.3, M-4767.4, M-4782.1, M-4782.2, M-4782.4, M-4801, M-4833.4, M-4869.2, M-4871.9, M-4872.1, M-4872.2, M-4985.2, M-4985.3, M-5009.3, M-5009.4, M-5009.5, M-5015.1, M-5015.2, M-5015.3, M-5015.4, M-5035.2, M-5048.1, M-5048.2, M-5050, M-5088.3, M-6039, M-6040.31, M-7012.3.
The collection is open for research.
Biography
Duane Norman Diedrich was born on January 3, 1935, to parents E. L. "Bud" and Blandina Diedrich, in Bloomington, Illinois. His father had a lengthy career as manager and superintendent for the S. S. Kresge Corporation (later the Kmart Corporation) and his mother worked as a German translator and secretary for State Farm Insurance. The family lived in multiple places in the Midwest, including Kalamazoo, Michigan (where D. N. Diedrich graduated from high school), and Peru, Anderson, and Muncie, Indiana.
"D. N. Diedrich graduated from the University of Michigan (A.B., 1956; M.A., 1957; Ph.D., 1961), and taught at U-M before leaving to pursue a career in academic teaching and administration elsewhere in the Midwest. Drawing upon an interest in history instilled in him by his parents and inspired by a personal letter from General Douglas MacArthur in 1952, Dr. Diedrich began to collect original manuscript letters, documents, speeches, musical manuscripts, and other primary sources pertinent to American history. His first purchase was an original signature of Theodore Roosevelt on a heavy-stock White House card." (Cheney J. Schopieray, One Hundred Selections from the Duane Norman Diedrich Collection of Manuscript Americana, 17th-20th Century. Ann Arbor, Mich.: William L. Clements Library, 2018: vii-viii).
"As a Professor of Speech, Dr. Diedrich incorporated historical manuscripts into his pedagogy. He brought authenticity and authority to his classroom instruction by showing students original speech drafts, podium notes, and varying printed versions of speeches. These materials added relevance, introduced and emphasized concepts, provided illustrations of speechwriting processes, and improved student engagement." (Schopieray, One Hundred ...: xii).
"Dr. Diedrich joined the Clements Library Associates during his graduate student days, in 1958, and served on the organization's Board of Governors beginning in 1975. On July 8, 1977, he made an agreement with the William L. Clements Library to build a collection of showpieces and research-rich manuscripts, by giving and adding items to his collection, and contributing funding and expertise. The collection was to include "original, authentic, and historical holograph manuscripts in the categories of religion, education, government, literature, art, music, business, science, and philanthropy." Working collaboratively with the Library, the Diedrich collection would complement existing holdings, add nuance to certain research areas, and help expand the Manuscripts Division's focus, especially to intellectual, artistic, and social history." (Schopieray, One Hundred...: viii).
Duane Norman Diedrich died at his home in Muncie, Indiana, on October 25, 2018, and is interred with his parents in Elm Ridge Mausoleum, Muncie.
The collection is arranged chronologically.
The Letters, Documents, and Other Manuscripts of the Duane Norman Diedrich Collection is a selection of individual items compiled by manuscript collector Duane Norman Diedrich (1935-2018) and the William L. Clements Library. The content of these materials reflect the life and interests of D. N. Diedrich, most prominently subjects pertinent to intellectual, artistic, and social history, education, speech and elocution, the securing of speakers for events, advice from elders to younger persons, and many others.
For an item-level description of the collection, with information about each manuscript, please see the box and folder listing below.
Subjects:
Apprentices.; Autographs--Collectors and collecting.; Banks and banking.; Charities.; Christianity.; Church buildings.; Composition (Language arts); Congregationalists.; Counseling.; Debt.; Education.; Education, Higher.; Elections.; Elocution.; Ethics.; Etiquette.; Fallen Timbers, Battle of, Ohio, 1794.; Guardianship.; Harvard University.; Holidays.; Indians of North America.; King Philip's War, 1675-1676.; Labor.; Libraries.; Music.; Oratory.; Parent and child.; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902.; Political parties.; Poverty.; Presidents--United States--Elections.; Printers--United States.; Quakers.; Schools.; School buildings.; Special events--Planning.; Speech.; Spiritualists.; Students.; Teachers.; Teachers--Salaries, etc.; Theater.; Transportation.; Tuition.; United States. Army.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--History--Revolution, 1776-1783.; United States--History--War of 1812.; United States. Marine Corps.; United States--Travel and description.; Washington, George, 1732-1799.; Women.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
Contributors:
Abbott, Jacob, 1803-1879.; Abington (Mass.); Abt, Franz, 1819-1885.; Adams, Charles Francis, 1807-1886.; Affleck, Thomas.; Aitken, Robert, 1735-1802.; Akst, Harry, 1894-1963.; Alden, Timothy, 1771-1839.; Alexander, Archibald, 1772-1851.; Alexander, James, 1691-1756.; Allen, Edward A. H. (Edward Augustus Holyoke), 1828-1898.; Allen, William H. (William Henry), 1808-1882.; American Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge.; Andrews, John, 1764-1845.; Angel, William Gardner, 1790-1858.; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906.; Arthur, T. S. (Timothy Shay), 1809-1885.; Ash, Patrick L.; Bacheldor, John Marvin, 1826-.; Banchen, Charles.; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891.; Bangs, Elijah Keeler, 1780-1856.; Baring-Gould, S. (Sabine), 1834-1924.; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956.; Barnes, Albert, 1798-1870.; Barnes, H. P.; Barry, Edward.; Barstow, C. H. (Charles H.), -1908.; Bartlett, John, 1820-1905.; Barton, W. K.; Beall, F.; Beardsley, Levi, 1785-1857.; Beasley, Frederic, 1777-1845.; Beaumont, Victor.; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887.; Beers, Nathan, 1753-1849.; Belknap, Jeremiah.; Belknap, Jeremy, 1744-1798.; Belknap, Samuel.; Benjamin, Park, 1809-1864.; Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858.; Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989.; Berrien, John MacPherson, 1781-1856.; Beveridge, Albert J. (Albert Jeremiah), 1862-1927.; Beverly, J. Parker.; Biddle, John, 1789-1859.; Biles, Captain.; Bingham, Amelia, 1869-1927.; Bird, Henry D.; Bishop, Henry R., (Henry Rowley), 1786-1855.; Blackburn, George, 1765-1823.; Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893.; Blair, Francis Preston, 1791-1876.; Bolmar, A. (Anthony), 1797-1861.; Boudinot, Elias, 1740-1821.; Boutwell, George S. (George Sewall), 1818-1905.; Brackenridge, H. M. (Henry Marie), 1786-1871.; Bradford, Alden, 1765-1843.; Bradley, Joseph H. (Joseph Habersham), 1802-1887.; Bradley, Tom P.; Bray, Thomas, 1658-1730.; Breed, George.; Brewer, Fred M.; Bridgman, Laura Dewey, 1829-1889.; Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893.; Brougham, John, 1810-1880.; Brown, Matthew, 1776-1853.; Browne, William B.; Brundage, George C.; Bucher, George J.; Bunnell, Charles P.; Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 1824-1881.; Burr, Jonathan Kelsey, 1825-1882.; Burritt, Elihu, 1810-1879.; Butler, David, 1763-1842.; Byrnes, Daniel, 1773-1851.; Byrns, William, ca. 1839-1875.; Cabot, George, 1752-1823.; Cady, Mary W.; Caldecott, Randolph, 1846-1886.; Calhoun, John C. (John Caldwell), 1782-1850.; Calhoun, William B. (William Barron), 1795-1865.; Campbell, Charles, 1807-1876.; Campbell, John Archibald, 1811-1889.; Campbell, Thomas F.; Carlisle, James M. (James Mandeville), 1814-1877.; Carmichael, M.; Carnegie, Dale, 1888-1955.; Carpenter, Karen, 1950-1983.; Carpenter, Richard, 1946-.; Carroll, Lewis, 1832-1898.; Carter, Galen.; Carver, Edwin J.; Catlin, George, 1796-1872.; Catlin, Putman.; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871.; Channing, W. H. (William Henry), 1810-1884.; Charles II, King of England, 1630-1685.; Chase, Stephen.; Chiffelle, Thomas P.; Christina, Queen of Sweden, 1626-1689.; Chrysler, Walter P. (Walter Percy), 1875-1940.; Clark, Joseph, 1751-1813.; Clarke, Charles G., Jr.; Clarke, M. St. Clair (Matthew St. Clair); Cleaveland, J. M.; Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910.; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908.; Clymer, George, 1739-1813.; Coffin, Robert Barry, 1826-1886.; Coggshall, Mary.; Coleman, Dan.; Colman, Benjamin, 1673-1747.; Cook, Robert.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Cooper, Edward, -1889.; Cooper, James Fenimore, 1789-1851.; Cooper, Peter, 1791-1883.; Cormick, Joseph G.; Coughenour, Henry.; Counts, Elijah.; Couper, J. Hamilton (James Hamilton), 1794-1866.; Cowles, William H.; Coxe, Richard S. (Richard Smith), 1792-1865.; Coxe, Tench, 1755-1824.; Craik, William, 1761-1814.; Crawford, David.; Critchley, William.; Cronkrite, J. B.; Crozer, John.; Cullen, Clarence Louis, -1922.; Cumming, Hooper, 1788-1825.; Cummins, R. K.; Curry, A. B.; Curtis, Benjamin Robbins, 1809-1874.; Cushing, Caleb, 1800-1879.; Cutting, John Browne, 1755?-1831.; Cutts, Richard, 1771-1845.; Cuyler, Theodore L. (Theodore Ledyard), 1822-1909.; Dana, Richard Henry, 1815-1882.; Dana, Richard Henry, Jr., 1815-1882.; Danforth, Royal W.; Davidson, John, 1738?-1794.; Davidson, Samuel.; Davis, David, 1815-1886.; Davis, John, 1787-1854.; Day, Jeremiah, 1773-1867.; Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829.; Delaplaine, Joseph, 1777-1824.; Dempster, William R. (William Richardson), 1809-1871.; Deneale, George, 1766-1818.; Denny, William H. (William Henry), 1796-.; Dent, G.; Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell), 1834-1928.; Derkheim, David.; Dessolles, Jean-Joseph Paul Augustin.; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Dey, Thomas.; Dickens, Catherine, 1815-1879.; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870.; Dickson, H. A.; Disney, Walt, 1901-1966.; Dixon, Nathan Fellows, 1774-1842.; Dixon, Thomas, 1864-1946.; Donn, Thomas C.; Donnelly, Ignatius, 1831-1901.; Douglass, H. Ford.; Dow, Neal, 1804-1897.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Dulany, Daniel, 1722-1797.; Dummer, Jeremiah, 1681-1739.; Duncan, John M. (John Morison), 1795?-1825.; Dunham, Daniel.; Duyckinck, Evert A. (Evert Augustus), 1816-1878.; Dwight, Theodore W. (Theodore William), 1822-1892.; Eaton, Samuel, 1737-1822.; Eddy, Samuel, 1769-1839.; Edwards, John.; Edwards, Jonathan, 1703-1758.; Egerton, Mathew.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Eisenhower, Earl D. (Earl Dewey), 1898-1968.; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926.; Eliot, Samuel.; Elliot, C. A.; Elliot, Jonathan, 1784-1846.; Ely, Ezra Stiles, 1786-1861.; Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882.; Ennis, Jesse.; Erskine, John, 1721-1803.; Evans, Evan.; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865.; Everett, Moses, 1750-1813.; Farmin, Uriel.; Fenner, Arthur, 1745-1805.; Ferre, Jonathan E.; Ferris, David, 1707-1779.; Fessenden, Benjamin, 1701-1746.; Fessenden, William Pitt, 1806-1869.; Fiero, Caroline.; Finney, Charles G., 1792-1875.; Fish, Hamilton, 1808-1893.; Flanagan, Virginia.; Ford, John.; Foster, John C.; Fowle, William B., 1795-1865.; Fowler, John W.; Fowler, O. S. (Orson Squire), 1809-1887.; Fredericksburg Academy (Fredericksburg, Va.); French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931.; Frost, Elizabeth.; Furness, William Henry, 1802-1896.; Gales, Joseph Jr., 1786-1860.; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849.; Gallaudet, Edward Miner, 1837-1917.; Gaston, William, 1788-1844.; Gates, J.; Gayley, Charles Mills, 1858-1932.; Geming, A. W.; Gerry, Elbridge, 1744-1814.; Gibbs, George.; Gideon, Jacob, 1779-1864.; Gilman, Arthur, 1837-1909.; Gilpin, Henry D. (Henry Dilworth), 1801-1860.; Githens, Willliam Henry Harrison, 1840-1923.; Goddard, J. H.; Gontz, J. D.; Goodale, Hannah, 1787-.; Gore, Christopher, 1758-1827.; Gough, John B. (John Bartholomew), 1817-1886.; Graves, Charles.; Grayson, Clifford Prevost, 1857-1951.; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872.; Greenleaf, Benjamin, 1732-1799.; Griffith, Henry Wharton.; Grote, Elisha.; Guiffrida, Francis.; Guilford, William.; Guthrie, James, 1792-1869.; Hackley, Charles William, 1809-1861.; Haley, S. G.; Hall, John L.; Hallsted, John B.; Hamilton, Alexander, 1786-1875.; Hamilton, James, Jr., 1786-1857.; Handy, W. C. (William Christopher), 1873-1958.; Haney, John.; Harrington, George.; Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901.; Haskins, Charles Homer, 1870-1937.; Hawley, Gideon, 1785-1870.; Hawley, Joseph R. (Joseph Roswell), 1826-1905.; Hawthorne, Julian, 1846-1934.; Hayden, Charles, 1764-.; Heath, Joseph.; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823.; Hedge, Frederic Henry, 1805-1890.; Hendricks, Thomas A. (Thomas Andrews), 1819-1885.; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878.; Henshaw, Charles.; Herrick, Cheesman Abiah, 1866-1956.; Higgins, Lizzie.; Higginson, Edward, d. 1922.; Hildeburn, Charles Swift Riché, 1855-1901.; Hill, Charles.; Hill, Thomas, 1818-1891.; Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904.; Hodge, Andrew.; Hoffman, Josef, 1876-1957.; Holbrook, Joseph C.; Holland, J. G. (Josiah Gilbert), 1819-1881.; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894.; Homer, Winslow, 1836-1910.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hopkinson, Joseph, 1770-1842.; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893.; Hosack, David, 1769-1835.; Houston, David Franklin, 1866-1940.; Hovey, Edmund Otis, 1801-1877.; Hughes, Thomas, 1822-1896.; Huntington, Daniel, 1816-1906.; Huntington, John.; Hyrne, Edward.; Idler, Jacob.; Ingersoll, Ernest, 1852-1946.; Ingersoll, Robert Green, 1833-1899.; Ireland, William. H., Jr.; Irving, Wag D. K.; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845.; Jackson, Joseph.; Jacobs, M. (Michael), 1808-1871.; Jay, John, 1817-1894.; Johnson, Abigail.; Johnson, Francis, 1792-1844.; Jolson, Al, 1886-1950.; Jones, C. S.; Jones, J.; Judson, A.; Kalmar, Bert, 1884-1947.; Keith, Agnes.; Keith, Thomas.; Kemble, Fanny, 1809-1893.; Kemp, A. L.; Kemp, John, 1763-1812.; Kennan, George, 1845-1924.; Kennedy, John F., Jr., 1960-1999.; Kern, Jerome, 1855-1945.; Keyser, Adolphus.; Kilpatrick, Judson, 1836-1881.; Kingsland, A.; Kingsland, D.; Kinney, Benjamin Harris, 1821-1888.; Knox, Henry, 1750-1806.; Krummer, John G.; Kryzanosky, Wenzel.; L. L. Todd & Company.; Lamb, Caroline, Lady, 1785-1828.; Lancaster, Joseph, 1778-1838.; Landon, Melville D. (Melville DeLancey), 1839-1910.; Lanman, Charles, 1819-1895.; Launy, Charity.; Laurence, Abraham R.; Lee, Edmund Jennings, 1797-1877.; Lee, Robert E. (Robert Edward), 1807-1870.; Lindsey, John, 1821-1887.; Link, H.; Linnell, Nathan Seabury.; Little, Marion N.; Little, Josiah, 1747-1830.; Little, Moses, 1724-1798.; Lloyd, James Hendrie, 1853-.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924.; Long, Robert, approximately 1602-1673.; Loring, S. D.; Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891.; Lukens, Cyrus.; Lyell, Charles, Sir, 1797-1875.; Lykins, Johnston, 1800?-1876.; Lyon, Mary, 1797-1849.; Maclaurin, Richard C. (Richard Cockburn), 1870-1920.; Mallbone, Thomas.; Malone, John.; Mason, William, 1829-1908.; Mather, John P. C. (John Perkins Cushing), 1816-1891.; Maurois, André, 1885-1967.; Mayo, Charles H. (Charles Horace), 1865-1939.; Mayo, William James, 1861-1939.; McCalla, John Moore, 1793-1873.; McCarthy, Eugene, 1916-2005.; McClan, Robert, Jr.; McCoy, Isaac, 1784-1846.; McDowell, Samuel.; McGuffey, William Holmes, 1800-1873.; McLain, William, 1806-1873.; M'Dowell, George, 1766 or 1767-1841.; Metcalfe, Thomas, 1780-1855.; Milledge, J.; Miller, Ferdinand von, 1813-1887.; Miller, Samuel, 1769-1850.; Milman, Henry Hart, 1791-1868.; Minor, Seth.; Moffit, Samuel.; Montgomery, James, 1771-1854.; Moodey, Samuel, 1676-1747.; Moody, Dwight Lyman, 1837-1899.; Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852.; Morris, Richard.; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806.; Morris, Staats Long, 1728-1800.; Morse, Jedediah, 1761-1826.; Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1791-1872.; Morton, J. Sterling (Julius Sterling), 1832-1902.; Morton, Nathaniel, 1613-1685.; Motley, John Lothrop, 1814-1877.; Mott, Lucretia, 1793-1880.; Murray, Catherine E.; Nast, Thomas, 1840-1902.; Nekervis, William.; Newburyport (Mass.). Selectmen.; Newhall, D. Wendell.; Newman, Jesse.; Nisbet, Charles, 1736-1804.; North, William, 1755-1836.; Nott, Eliphalet, 1773-1866.; Noyes, Joseph.; Obama, Barack.; Oden, Benjamin.; Ogden, John Cosens, 1751-1800.; O'Neal, Manuel M.; Orcutt, Samuel.; Ord, George, 1781-1866.; Otis, Harrison Gray, 1765-1848.; Otto, William T., 1816-1905.; Ould, Robert.; Owen, Robert, 1771-1858.; Owens, Mary.; Owens, Thomas.; Packard, Abel.; Palmer, Erastus Dow, 1817-1904.; Park, Edwards Amasa, 1808-1900.; Park, Laura Hall, 1828-1875.; Parker, Francis Edward, 1821-1886.; Parker, Theodore, 1810-1860.; Parsons, Chase Prescott, 1832-1879.; Parsons, Josiah.; Patten, Richard.; Peabody, George Foster, 1852-1938.; Peabody, George, 1795-1869.; Peabody, Jacob.; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865.; Pearson, E. A.; Peary, Robert E. (Robert Edwin), 1856-1920.; Peck, Jesse T. (Jesse Truesdell), 1811-1883.; Pells, C. L.; Pepys, Samuel, 1633-1703.; Perit, John W.; Phelps, Almira Hart Lincoln, 1793-1884.; Phelps, Amos A. (Amos Augustus), 1805-1847.; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829.; Pierce, Franklin, 1804-1869.; Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892.; Pitman, Isaac, 1813-1897.; Poe, Neilson.; Polhaus, J. W.; Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887.; Potte
Genre Terms:
Bills of exchange.; Documents (object genre); Certificates.; Circulars (fliers); Diaries.; Engravings (prints); Letters (correspondence); Lists (document genres); Notebooks.; Pamphlets.; Photographic postcards.; Photographs.; Poems.; Receipts (financial records); Speeches (documents); Weather diaries
- Letters, Documents, and Other Manuscripts, Duane Norman Diedrich Collection, 1595-2007
  - 1595 November 6. Maria de Urieta DS (with attachments) to Juan Perez de Aguirre; San Luis Minas de Potosi, [Mexico], 12 pages; Loan of money by Juan Perez de Aguirre to Maria de Urieta (free woman of African descent), guaranteed by Juan de Vargas. [In Spanish. No translation.] (Box 1)
  - 1645 June 5. John Winthrop ADS; [Boston, Massachusetts], 1 page; "Joan the wife of Jo:Stowe of Hull sworne sayth that she knoweth Purnell the wife of Jo:Bartoll & did come over in the shippe with her, & she sayth that her carriage was vere light, & havinge her Cabin near this attestant, she did once or twice rise in the night from her children & they would crye in her absence; & she was verye familiar with the Boatswain & would oft. sitt drinking tobacco wth him: & this is the worst that this Attestant did see or knowe by her."
  - 1652 August 25. Christina ADS to Johann Olafsson Kiernin; Stockholm, [Sweden], 1 page; Official document, with seal [Iin Swedish. No translation].